<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>semantic-search on ashish.one</title>
    <link>https://ashish.one/tags/semantic-search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in semantic-search on ashish.one</description>
    <image>
      <title>ashish.one</title>
      <url>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/dcb52889deff3e5017a18de40c57add8?s=200</url>
      <link>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/dcb52889deff3e5017a18de40c57add8?s=200</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.115.4</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:12:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ashish.one/tags/semantic-search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GIDS 2024 - Smart Search with RAG: Elasticsearch Meets Language Models</title>
      <link>https://ashish.one/talks/gids-2024-rag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:12:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashish.one/talks/gids-2024-rag/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s data-driven world, just having a search engine is not enough; the key is making it smart. Enter Elasticsearch Relevance Engine (ESRE) augmented with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), a powerful solution that marries Elasticsearch’s superior search capabilities with Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT for precise, contextual querying over proprietary datasets. This session is a hands-on guide that will show you how to amplify the power of Elasticsearch with advanced LLMs.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>In today&rsquo;s data-driven world, just having a search engine is not enough; the key is making it smart. Enter Elasticsearch Relevance Engine (ESRE) augmented with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), a powerful solution
that marries Elasticsearch’s superior search capabilities with Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT for precise, contextual querying over proprietary datasets. This session is a hands-on guide that will show you how to amplify the power of Elasticsearch with advanced LLMs.</p>
<p>Key Takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn how to supercharge Elasticsearch&rsquo;s BM25 algorithm with semantic search for results that are not just relevant but contextually accurate.</li>
<li>Discover how to plug in Large Language Models like OpenAI&rsquo;s ChatGPT to enable context-aware question-answering over your proprietary data.</li>
<li>Gain insights into the latest advancements in vector search within Lucene and Elasticsearch.</li>
<li>A quick live demo: Experience first-hand how ESRE, empowered by RAG, transforms a basic search query into a context-rich, highly relevant result..</li>
</ul>
<p>This talk is for you if you&rsquo;re grappling with search relevance issues and are looking for innovative ways to make your search smarter and more efficient. Whether you&rsquo;re a software developer, data engineer, or ML enthusiast, this session will equip you with the skills you need to build next-generation search capabilities.</p>
<h2 id="talk-video">Talk video</h2>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r1jO4TglsEg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
