<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ashish.one</title>
    <link>https://ashish.one/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ashish.one</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ashish Tiwari</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 15:24:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ashish.one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Part 2] How to setup alertmanager and send alerts ?</title>
      <link>https://ashish.one/blogs/setup-alertmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 15:24:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashish.one/blogs/setup-alertmanager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In PART - 1, We have successfully setup Prometheus and exporters. In this part, we are going to setup alertmanager and will send our first alert.
Alertmanager is software that is maintained by the prometheus and it is written in Go. It takes care of deduplicating, grouping, and routing them to the correct receiver integration such as email, PagerDuty, or OpsGenie. It also takes care of silencing and inhibition of alerts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1] How To Setup Prometheus And Exporters For Alerts And Monitoring?</title>
      <link>https://ashish.one/blogs/setup-prometheus-and-exporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:20:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashish.one/blogs/setup-prometheus-and-exporters/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, many times you would have worried, whether your services are up and running or not. Not only that, sometimes as an infrastructure guy you might be also worried about your server’s health too. What is the current RAM or disk utilization? or whether they are going to be fully occupied which in turn can completely bring the system down. These are just the basics and in fact there are tons of more such things which need to be monitored and fixed in everyday&amp;rsquo;s life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should be the value of max_gram and min_gram in Elasticsearch?</title>
      <link>https://ashish.one/blogs/min-gram-and-max-gram-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:20:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashish.one/blogs/min-gram-and-max-gram-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>I was working on elasticsearch and the requirement was to implement like query “%text%” ( like mysql %like% ). We could use wildcard, regex or query string but those are slow. Hence i took decision to use ngram token filter for like query. It was quickly implemented on local and works exactly i want.
The problem To know the actual behavior, I implemented the same on staging server. I found some problem while we start indexing on staging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://ashish.one/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:11:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashish.one/about/</guid>
      <description>Having 4+ Year experience in Software &amp;amp; Email Industry. Started as software engineer, Now i am Developer evangelist @ Pepipost, Where i am responsible for Reports management, database management &amp;amp; application development. I also working on platform architecture to handling heavy traffic of events which is combination of queues stack, Daemons and various services.
As a Developer evangelist got opportunity to work with end users. I have been fortunate to work with various technology like Elasticserach, go, perl, Java etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>